好吧，让我们今天开始，实际上今天和明天我
all right well let's get started
today and indeed today and tomorrow I'm
我都想谈谈木筏，因为我希望它对您有帮助
gonna talk about raft both because I
hope it'll be helpful you for you in
通过实验室进行植入，还因为您知道这只是一个案例研究
implanting though the labs and also
because you know it's just a case study
在如何使状态机复制正确的细节中，
in the details of how to get state
machine replication correct so we have
问题的介绍，您可能已经注意到容错模式
introduction to the problem you may have
noticed a pattern in fault-tolerant
到目前为止，我们研究的系统之一是MapReduce复制
systems that we've looked at so far
one is that MapReduce replicates
计算，但复制受控制，整个计算是
computation but the replication is
controlled the whole computation is
由一个大师控制的另一个例子，我想引起您的注意
controlled by a single master another
example I'd like to draw your attention
就是GFS将数据复制为该主备份方案
to is that GFS replicates data right as
this primary backup scheme for
复制文件的实际内容，但它依赖于单个主文件
replicating the actual contents of files
but it relies on a single master to
选择谁是每个数据的主要对象另一个示例vmware ft
choose who the primary is for every
piece of data another example vmware ft
在主虚拟机和备份上复制计算写操作
replicates computational write on a
primary virtual machine and a backup
虚拟机，但是为了弄清楚下一步是做什么的
virtual machine but in order to figure
out what to do next if one of them seems
如果失败，则依赖于单个测试和设置服务器来帮助选择帮助
to a fail it relies on a single test and
set server to help the choose to help it
如果有一些备份，请确保恰好是备份的主要备份之一
ensure that exactly one of the primary
of the backup takes over if there's some
一种失败，因此在所有这三种情况下都确保存在复制
kind of failure so in all three of these
cases sure there was a replication
系统，但隐藏在复制系统的某个角落
system but sort of tucked away in a
corner in the replication system there
是某些方案，要求单个实体做出关键决策
was some scheme where a single entity
was required to make a critical decision
在我们关心的情况下，谁是主要的
about who the primary was in the cases
we care about so a very nice thing about
由一个实体来决定谁将成为主要实体是因为它不能
having a single entity decide who's
gonna be the primary is that it can't
不同意自己的权利，只有其中一项做出一些决定，那就是
disagree with itself right there's only
one of it makes some decision that's the
做出决定，但由一个实体决定的坏事就像谁
decision it made but the bad thing about
having a single entity decide like who
主要是它本身就是一个单点故障，因此您可以
the primary is is that it itself as a
single point of failure and so you can
查看我们已经查看过的这些系统，这在一定程度上推动了
view these systems that we've looked at
it sort of pushing the real heart of the
容错机械陷入一个小角落
fault tolerance
Machinery into a little corner that is
如果有一个实体，则决定谁将成为主要实体的单一实体
the single entity that decides who's
going to be the primary if there's a
现在失败这整个事情是关于如何避免大脑分裂的原因
failure now this whole thing is about
how to avoid split brain the reason why
我们必须非常谨慎地做出有关
we have to have have to be extremely
careful about making the decision about
如果发生故障，谁应该是主要的，否则我们将面临分裂的风险
who should be the primary if there's a
failure is that otherwise we risks split
大脑，让这一点变得非常清楚，我会提醒您
brain and just make this point super
clear I'm gonna just remind you what the
问题是，为什么它是一个严重的问题，所以假设例如
problem is and why it's a serious
problem so supposing for example where
我们要构建自己的复制测试并设置服务器
we want to build ourselves a replicated
test and set server that is we're
担心vmware ft依赖此测试并将服务器设置为
worried about the fact that vmware ft
relies on this test and set server to
选择主要的是谁，让我们建立一个复制的测试集服务器
choose who the primary is so let's build
a replicated testing set server i'm
要做到这一点，它将被打破，这只是为什么的原因的一个例证
gonna do this it's gonna be broken it's
just an illustration for why why it's
很难得到这个，但是大脑问题正确了，所以你知道我们要
difficult to get this but brain problem
correctly so you know we're gonna
想象我们有一个网络，也许还有两个应该是
imagine we have a network and maybe two
servers which are supposed to be
测试和设置服务的副本已连接，您可能知道两个客户端
replicas of our test and set service
connected and you know maybe two clients
他们需要知道现在谁是主要的，或者实际上可能是这些
they need to know who's the primary
right now or actually maybe these
在这种情况下，客户端是vmware ft中备份的主要对象，因此如果是
clients in this case are the primary in
the back up in vmware ft so if it's a
测试并设置服务，那么您就知道这两个数据库主要是服务器启动的
test and set service then you know both
these databases mostly servers start out
他们的状态即这次试飞的状态归零，并且
with their state that is the state of
this test flight back in zero and the
客户可以发送的一项操作是测试和设置操作，即
one operation their clients can send is
the test and set operation which is
应该将复制服务的标志设置为一个，所以我应该
supposed to set the flag of the
replicated service to one so i should
设置两个副本，然后返回旧值，因此它本质上是一种
set both copies and then return the old
value so it's essentially acts as a kind
简化的锁定服务器还可以，所以问题情况令人担忧
of simplified lock server okay so the
problem situation the lowly worried
当客户端可以与其中一台服务器通信但无法通信时，就会出现关于裂脑的问题
about split-brain arises when a client
can talk to one of the servers but can't
与对方交谈，因此我们在想，当客户发送请求时
talk to the other so we're imagining
either that when clients send a request
他们发送给两个我只是要假设现在，几乎没有
they send it to both I'm just gonna
assume that now and almost doesn't
重要的是，让我们假设协议是客户端应该发送
matter so let's assume that the protocol
is that the clients supposed to send
通常对这两个服务器的任何请求，以及我们知道您需要的某种方式
ordinarily any request to both servers
and somehow we you know we need
想一想如果服务器之一不响应，客户端应该怎么做
think through what the clients should do
if one of the server's doesn't respond
正确或如果其中一台服务器似乎已获得系统应该怎么做
right or what the system should do if
one of the server seems to gotten
快速响应，让我们想象一下，现在客户端可以与服务器之一联系，但是
responsive so let's imagine now the
client one can contact server one but
不是服务器二，系统应该如何应对？一种可能性是因为我们
not server two how should the system
react one possibility is for is that we
想好，你知道，天哪，我们当然不想只跟客户交谈
think well you know gosh we certainly
don't want to just talk to client to
服务器一，因为如果我们进行设置，那将使第二个副本不一致
server one because that would leave the
second replica inconsistent if we set
将此值设为1，但也未将此值设为1
this value to one but didn't also set
this value to one
所以也许规则应该是总是要求客户与之交谈
so maybe the rule should be that the
client is always required to talk to
将两个副本复制到两个服务器以进行任何操作，并且不应允许
both replicas to both servers for any
operation and shouldn't be allowed to
只是和他们中的一个说话，为什么是错误的答案，所以我们的规则是o
just talk to one of them so why is that
the wrong answer so the rule is o in our
客户端始终需要与两个副本进行对话的复制系统
replicated system the clients always
require to talk to both replicas in
事实上，要取得进步比和别人说话更糟
order to make progress at all in fact
it's worse it's worse than talking to a
单个服务器，因为如果这些服务器之一是
single server because now the system has
a problem if either of these servers is
崩溃，或者至少无法与非复制服务进行通话
crashed or or you can't talk to it at
least with a non replicated service
您仅依赖一台服务器，但是在这里，我们两台服务器都必须很多
you're only depending on one server but
here we am both servers have to be a lot
如果我们要求客户与两台服务器通话，那么两台服务器必须处于活动状态
if we require the client to talk to both
servers then both servers has to be live
因此我们可能无法要求客户实际上您知道等待两者
so we can't possibly require the client
to actually you know wait for both
服务器要响应，如果我们没有容错能力，我们需要它能够
servers to respond if we don't have
fault tolerance we need it to be able to
继续进行，所以另一个明显的答案是，如果客户不能同时与双方交谈
proceed so another obvious answer is
that if the client can't talk to both
好吧，它只是和一个可以交谈的人交谈，并计算其他人的死亡
well it just talks to the one who can
talk to and figures the other ones dead
所以怎么了，为什么那也不是正确的答案
so what's up why is that also not the
right answer
令人不安的情况是，如果另一台服务器实际上还活着，那么假设
the troubling scenario is if the other
server is actually alive so suppose the
实际的问题或遇到的不是该服务器崩溃了
actual problem or encountering is not
that this server crashed which would be
对我们有好处，但更糟糕的是，
good for us but the much worse issue
that something went wrong with the
网络电缆，并且该客户端可以通话爬网，可以与服务器通话
network cable and that this client can
talk to climb one can talk to server one
但不是第二台服务器，可能还有其他一些客户端
but not server two and there's maybe
some other client out there that conduct
服务器二而不是服务器一，所以如果我们制定一个规则，即客户可以通话
a server two but not server one so if we
make the rule that if a client can talk
对两台服务器来说都可以，以便可以容错。
to both servers that it's okay in order
to be fault tolerant that I just talked
然后一个人不可避免地会发生什么事，说这根电缆会断线
to one then what's just inevitably gonna
happen said this cable is gonna break
从而将网络减少一半，一个客户端将发送测试并设置请求
thus cutting the network in half client
one is gonna send a test and set request
服务器一台服务器，您会知道将其状态设置为一并返回
to server one server one will you know
set it state to one and return the
客户1的先前值为零，这意味着客户妈妈会认为
previous value of zero to client one and
so that mean client mom will think it
有锁，如果是VMware ft服务器，它将认为这可能是接管
has the lock and if it's a VMware ft
server will think it can be takeovers
主要但此副本仍为零，现在如果客户要
primarily but this replica still of zero
in it all right so now if client to
谁还会发送测试和设置请求给您，您会知道将其发送给什么价格
who've also sends a test and set request
to you know what price to send them to
都看到服务器一台似乎已关闭，这遵循的原则是您
both sees that server one appears to be
down follows the rule that says well you
只是发送到一台服务器，但您可以与之交谈，它也会认为它
just send to the one server but you can
talk to then it will also think that it
要么安静，因为客户端，您也认为它获得了锁，
would either quiet because client you
also think that it acquired the lock and
所以现在您知道我们是否正在构想该测试，并且该服务器将
so now you know if we were imagining
this test and that server was going to
与和一起使用时，我们并没有同时复制这两个VMware
be used with the and where ft we have
not both replicas both of these VMware
我认为这些机器本身可以是主要的，而无需咨询
machines I think they could be primary
by themselves without consulting the
其他服务器，这是一个完全失败，因此通过此设置和两个
other server so that's a complete
failure so with this set up and two
服务器似乎我们有这个，我们只需要选择要么等待
servers it seemed like we had this we
just had to choose either you wait for
两者都不能容错，或者您只等一个而又不容错
both and you're not fault-tolerant or
you wait for just one and you're not
正确，然后是我们的正确版本，通常称为裂脑
correct and then our correct version
it's often called split brain so
大家都很好看
everybody see this well
所以这基本上是直到80年代后期，人们
so this was basically where things stood
until the late 80s and when people but
人们确实想构建您知道的复制系统，例如那些
people did want to build replicated
systems you know like the computers that
控制电话交换机或运行银行的计算机
control telephone switches or the
computers that ran banks you know there
当我们花费大量金钱来获得可靠
was placer when we spend a huge amount
of money in order to have reliable
服务，因此他们将进行复制，以构建复制的系统，并且
service and so they would replicate they
would build replicated systems and the
他们会处理的方式，然后他们会复制但尝试
way they would deal then way would that
they would have replication but try to
排除大脑裂开这是两种技术，一种是
rule out of rule out split brain it's a
couple of techniques one is they would
建立一个不会失败的网络，通常这意味着什么，实际上
build a network that could not fail and
so usually what that means and in fact
你们使用的网络基本上不会在所有时间中断
you guys use networks that essentially
cannot fail all the time the wires
在笔记本电脑内部，您知道将CPU连接到DRAM的确有效
inside your laptop you know connecting
the CPU to the DRAM are effectively what
您知道在CPU和DRAM之间不会出现故障的网络，因此
you know a network that cannot fail
between the between your CPU and DRAM so
你知道合理的假设和很多钱，你知道
you know with reasonable assumptions and
lots of money and you know sort of
精心控制的身体状况，例如您不需要电缆
carefully controlled physical situation
like you don't want to have a cable
在地板上偷偷摸摸地有人可以踩到你知道这一定是
snaking across the floor that somebody
can step on you know it's got to be
物理设计的网络可以确保您不会失败
physically designed set up with a
network that cannot fail you can rule
分裂大脑这是一个假设，但有足够的钱人
out split brain it's bit of an
assumption but with enough money people
非常接近这一点，因为如果网络无法失败，则基本上意味着
get quite close to this because if the
network cannot fail that basically means
客户端无法与服务器对话，这意味着第二台服务器必须停机
that the client can't talk to a server
to that means server two must be down
因为它不可能是网络故障，所以这是一种方法
because it can't have been the network
malfunctioning so that was one way that
人们构建了不会遭受脑裂的复制系统
people sort of built replication systems
it didn't suffer from split brain
另一种可能性是让一些人来解决问题
another possibility would be to have
some human beings sort out the problem
那是不会自动做任何事情，而是让您认识的客户
that is don't automatically do anything
instead have the clients you know by
默认客户端始终必须等待您知道两个副本都响应或
default clients always have to wait for
you know both replicas to respond or
某些事情永远不允许继续进行，但你可以知道
something never allowed to proceed with
just one of them but you can you know
叫某人的哔哔声离开某人去机房，
call somebody's beeper to go off some
human being goes to the machine room and
看起来两个副本，然后关闭其中一个以确保它是
sort of looks at the two replicas and
either turns one off to make sure it's
肯定已经死亡或验证其中一个确实存在
definitely dead
or verifies that one of them has indeed
坠毁，如果另一个还活着，那么您实际上是在使用人类作为
crashed and if the other is alive and so
you're essentially using the human as a
因为抢七局和人是一个人，你知道他们是否是计算机
as the tie breaker and the human is a
you know if they were a computer it
如果您自己如此，那么很长一段时间人们都会使用
would be a single point if you
themselves so for a long time people use
这些方案之一是为了构建复制系统，
one of the other these schemes in order
to build replicated systems and it's not
你知道他们可以被创造出来，人类不会很快做出反应，
you know they can be made to work the
humans don't respond very quickly and
无法失败的网络是昂贵的，但并非不可能，但是它
the network that cannot fail is
expensive but it's not not doable but it
事实证明，您实际上可以构建可以正常工作的自动故障转移系统
turned out that you can actually build
automated failover systems that can work
面对易碎的网络可能会失败
correctly in the face of flaky networks
of networks that could fail on the can
进行分区，以便将网络分成两半，由双方共同操作
partition so this split of the network
in half where the two sides operate they
不能互相交谈，通常被称为分区，而洞察力很大
can't talk to each other that's usually
called a partition and the big insight
人们想出了建立自动复制系统
that people came up with in order to
build automated replication systems that
不要遭受脑裂的困扰，这是多数表决的想法
don't suffer from split brain is the
idea of a majority vote this is a
几乎在筏子中像其他句子一样出现的概念
concept that shows up in like every
other sentence practically in the raft
进行第一步的基本方法是
paper sort of fundamental way of
proceeding the first step is to have an
服务器的数量是奇数，而不是偶数，例如一个缺陷是
odd number of servers instead of an even
number of servers like one flaw here is
在这里分割的两侧有点太对称了
that it's a little bit too symmetric all
right the two sides of the split here
只是它们看起来一样所以他们运行相同的软件
just they just look the same so they run
the same software they're gonna do the
同样的事情，那不是很好，但是如果您的服务器数量奇数，那么
same thing and that's not good but if
you have an odd number of servers then
它不再是对称的，至少会有一个网络分裂
it's not symmetric anymore right at
least a single network split will be
大概一侧有两台服务器，另一侧有一台服务器，它们
presumably two servers on one side and
one server on the other side and they
完全不会对称，这是多数投票多数的一部分
won't be symmetric at all and that's
part of what majority vote majority
投票方案吸引了如此基本的想法，因此您拥有数量奇数的服务器
voting schemes are appealing to so basic
ideas you have an odd number of servers
为了取得任何进展，因此在筏子中选出一个领导者或引起一个日志
in order to make progress of any kind so
in raft elect a leader or cause a log
为了在每个步骤上取得任何进展而必须提交的条目
entry to be committed in order to make
any progress at each step you have to
将一半以上的服务器组装成一半以上的服务器
assemble a majority of the server's more
than half more than half of all the
服务器以批准该步骤，例如投票要求开会或接受
servers in order to sort of approve that
step like vote for a meet or accept a
新的日志条目并将其提交，因此您知道最直接的方法是两个
new log entry and commit it so you know
the most straightforward way is that two
或三台服务器需要执行任何操作
or three servers required to do anything
当然有效的原因之一是，如果有分区，就不会有分区
one reason this works of course is that
if there's a partition there can't be
一个以上具有大部分服务器分区的分区是一种方法
more than one partition with a majority
of the server's in it that's one way to
看看这个分区中可以有一个服务器，但它不是大多数
look at this a partition can have one
server in it which it's not a majority
或者也许可以有两个，但是如果一个分区有两个，那么另一个分区
or maybe you can have two but if one
partition has two then the other
分区中只能有一个服务器，因此永远无法
partition has to have only one server in
it and therefore will never be able to
聚集多数，将无法取得进展，只能完全
assemble a majority and won't be able to
make progress and just to be totally
很清楚，当我们谈论多数时，总是占多数
clear when we're talking about a
majority it's always a majority out of
所有服务器不仅是实时服务器，这是令人困惑的一点
all of the server's not just a live
servers this is the point that confused
我很长一段时间，但如果您的系统具有三台服务器，也许还有一些
me for a long time but if you have a
system with three servers and maybe some
他们中的一些失败了，或者如果您需要大多数组装的话，
of them have failed or something if you
need to assemble in the majority it's
即使您知道一个失败了，也总是三分之二
always two out of three even if you know
that one has failed the majority is
总是在服务器总数中有一个更一般的
always out of the total number of
servers there's a more general
之所以这样表述，是因为多数票制中三分之二
formulation of this because a majority
voting system in which two out of three
需要取得进展，使其可以在一台服务器的故障中幸存下来
are required to make progress it can
survive the failure of one server right
如果需要的话，任何两台服务器足以使进度
any two servers are enough to make
progress if you need to be able to if
您知道自己担心服务器的可靠性，然后
you're you know you worried about how
reliable your servers are or then you
可以构建具有更多服务器的系统，因此更一般的表述是
can build systems that have more servers
and so the more general formulation is
如果您有两个F +1服务器，那么您可以承受，所以如果是三个
if you have two F + 1 servers then you
can withstand you know so if it's three
这意味着F是一个，而具有三个服务器的系统可以容忍F个服务器
that means F is one and the system with
three servers you can tolerate F servers
第一步失败，仍然继续
step one failure and still keep going
好吧，这些通常称为仲裁系统，因为三分之二是
all right often these are called quorum
systems because the two out of three is
有时举行法定人数，所以我已经提到过一个物业
sometimes held a quorum okay so one
property I've already mentioned about
这些多数表决系统是，最多一个分区可以拥有多数
these majority voting systems is that at
most one partition can have a majority
因此，如果网络分区了，我们就不能同时拥有一半
and therefore if the networks
partitioned we can't have both halves of
网络使进步的另一个更微妙的事情是
the network making progress another more
subtle thing that's going on here is
如果您始终需要大多数服务器才能继续
that if you always need a majority of
the servers to proceed and you go
通过一系列连续的操作，其中到达操作
through a sort of succession of
operations in which reach operations
有人聚集了多数席位，就像您知道领导人的选票，还是说
somebody assembled a majority like you
know votes for leaders or let's say
领导人的选票到了，然后在每一步中，您为此聚集的多数
votes for leaders arrived then at every
step the majority you assemble for that
步骤必须包含至少一台以前占多数的服务器
step must contain at least one server
that was in the previous majority that
至少一台服务器中有两个多数是重叠的，实际上
is any two majorities overlap in at
least one server and it's really that
财产比筏子赖以避免大脑分裂的其他任何东西都重要
property more than anything else that
raft is relying on to avoid split brain
这是事实，例如，当你有一个领导者时，一个成功的领导者
it's the fact that for example when you
have a leader a successful leader
选举和领导人从多数票中选出，保证多数票通过
election and leader assembles votes from
a majority its majority is guaranteed to
与以前的领导人多数重叠，例如新的
overlap with the previous leaders
majority and so for example the new
保证领导者知道前任领导者使用的任期编号
leader is guaranteed to know about the
term number used by the previous leader
因为它的多数派与之前的领导人多数派重叠，并且
because it's a majority overlaps with
the previous leaders majority and
历届领导人中的大多数人都知道历届领导人
everybody in the previous leaders
majority knew about the previous leaders
任期编号与前任领导者相似
term number
similarly anything the previous leader
本可以提交的必须存在于筏中的大多数服务器中，并且
could have committed must be present in
a majority of the servers in raft and
因此，任何新的领导者多数都必须至少与一台服务器重叠
therefore any new leaders majority must
overlap at at least one server with
前任领导人的每一项承诺承诺，都是其重要原因
every committed entry from the previous
leader this is a big part of why it is
包裹是正确的
that wrapped is correct
有关多数投票制一般概念的任何疑问
any questions about the general concept
of majority voting systems
这些肌肉广告服务器
these muscle ad servers
这可能是相交的东西，也许论文中的六个解释了如何
it's possible intersection something
maybe six in the paper explains how to
添加它或更改服务器集，可能您需要在一个
add it or change the set of servers and
it's possible you need to do it in a
长时间运行的系统，如果您将系统运行五十年，您就会知道
long-running system if you're running
your system for five ten years you know
一段时间后，您将需要更换服务器
you're gonna need to replace the servers
after a while you know one of them fails
永久性或升级或将机房移至其他计算机
permanently or you upgrade or you move
machine rooms to a different machine
您真正需要的机房必须能够支持不断变化的服务器组，因此
room you really do need to be able to
support changing sets of servers so
那当然不是每天都会发生，但这是
that's a it certainly doesn't happen
every day but it's a critical part of
这些系统的长期或可维护性，您知道英国皇家空军
this or a long-term maintainability of
these systems and you know the RAF
作者有点自以为是，他们有一个解决方案
authors sort of pat themselves on the
back that they have a scheme that deals
他们也可能这样做，因为它很复杂，所以使用
with this which as well they might
because it's complex all right so using
这个想法在大约1990年左右提出了两个大致相同的系统
意识到您可以使用多数投票制的时间
time that realized that you could use
this majority voting system to kind of
基本上避免使用避免大脑分裂的明显不可能
get around the apparent impossibility of
avoiding split brain by using basically
通过使用三台服务器（而不是两台）并获得多数票，并在其中一台
by using three servers instead of two
and taking majority votes and in one of
这些非常早期的系统被称为Paxos，英国皇家空军的论文谈到了
these very early systems was called
Paxos the RAF paper talks about this a
这些早期系统中的另一个被称为视图图章
lot and another of these very early
systems was called view stamp
复制previa des vs r4视图戳复制，即使Paxos
replication a previa des vs r4 view
stamp replication and even though Paxos
到目前为止，pod是该部门筏中最广泛使用的系统
pod is by far the more widely known
system in this department raft is
实际上在设计上更接近设计以查看陈述，很少使用图章
actually closer to design in design to
view statment few stamp application
这是麻省理工学院的人发明的，所以十年来有种法律
which was invented by people at MIT and
so there's a sort of a law many decade
这些系统的历史，它们才真正走到最前沿并开始
history of these systems and they only
really came to the forefront and started
被部署在大型分布式sisty系统中使用了大约15年
being used a lot in deployed big
distributed sisty systems about 15 years
早在最初发明它们的15年后，好吧，让我谈谈
ago a good 15 years after they were
originally invented okay so let me talk
关于拉丝
about Rath now
筏是一种旨在包含在某些服务中的图书馆形式
raft is a takes the form of a library
intended to be included in some service
应用程序，因此，如果您具有复制服务，则
application so if you have a replicated
service that each of the replicas in the
服务将是一些您知道会收到rpcs的应用程序代码，或者
service is gonna be some application
code which you know receives rpcs or
东西加上一个筏库，并且筏库相互协作
something plus a raft library and the
raft libraries cooperate with each other
意味着复制可保持复制，因此单个软件的软件概述
to mean replication maintain replication
so sort of software overview of a single
筏副本是在顶部，我们可以想到具有
raft replica is that at the top we can
think of the replicas having the
应用程序代码，因此它可能是针对实验3的键值服务器，所以也许
application code so it might be for lab
3 a key-value server so maybe we have
一些键值服务器，并且在某种状态下，应用程序具有以下状态：
some key value server and in a state the
application has state that raft is
帮助它管理复制状态，对于键值服务器，它将是
helping it manage replicated state and
for a key value server it's going to be
键和值的表，下一层是筏层，因此键
a table of keys and values the next
layer down is a raft layer so the key
价值服务器会在筏中进行make函数调用，
value server is gonna sort of make
function calls into raft and they're
会来回itch，筏子保持一点状态
gonna chitchat back and forth a little
bit and raft keeps a little bit of state
您可以在图2中看到它，对于我们来说，这实际上是最关键的部分
you can see it in Figure 2 and for our
purposes really the most critical piece
状态是筏有操作日志和3次呼吸的系统
of state is that raft has a log of
operations and a system with 3 breath
会导致我们实际上要让您知道3台服务器
will cause we're actually gonna have you
know 3 servers that have exactly the
相同的结构，希望坐在相同的数据
same identical structure and hopefully
the very same data sitting in sitting at
两层
both layers
除此之外，会有客户，而游戏就是这样
right outside of this there's gonna be
clients and the game is that so we have
你知道客户1和客户两个客户群
you know client 1 and client two whole
bunch of clients the clients don't
真正了解客户，您只知道需要
really know the clients are you know
just external code that needs to be able
使用服务，希望的是客户真的不需要知道
to use the service and the hope is the
clients won't really need to be aware
他们正在与复制服务进行通信，该复制服务与
that they're talking to a replicated
service that to the clients that are
看起来几乎就像一台服务器，而他们与一台服务器通信，因此
looking almost like it's just one server
and they talked with one server and so
客户端实际上将客户端请求发送给应用程序的密钥
the clients actually send client
requests to the key to the application
当前领导者的图层是筏中当前领导者的副本，因此
layer of the current leader the replica
that's the current leader in raft and so
这些将成为您知道密钥的数据库的应用程序级别请求
these are gonna be you know application
level requests for a database for a key
值服务器，这些服务器可能放在获取请求中，而您知道该请求需要一个密钥和
value server these might be put in get
requests you know put takes a key and a
值并更新表，并要求服务获取当前密钥
value and updates the table and get
asked the service to get the current key
对应于某个键的当前值，所以这样就无关紧要
current value corresponding to some key
so this like has nothing about to do
用木筏不管是什么，都只是客户端-服务器交互的一种
with raft it's just sort of
client-server interaction for whatever
我们正在构建的服务，但是一旦其中一个命令从
service we're building but once one of
these commands gets sent from the
请求是从服务器的客户端发送的，实际发生的是您
requests get sent from the clients of
the server what actually happens is you
知道在非复制服务器上应用程序代码想要执行此操作
know on a non replicated server the
application code would like execute this
请求并说更新表格并回复书，但不在木筏中
request and say update the table and
response to a book but not in a raft
如果假设客户端向领导发送请求，则复制服务
replicated service instead if assuming
the client sends a request to leader
真正发生的是应用层只是发送请求
what really happens is the application
layer simply sends the request the
客户要求到木筏层说看起来你知道这是一个请求
clients request down into the raft layer
to say look you know here's a request
请把它提交到复制的日志中，并告诉我何时
please get it committed into the
replicated log and tell me when you're
完成，所以在这一点上，木筏彼此缩，直到所有
done and so at this point the rafts
chitchat with each other until all the
副本占多数，副本将此新操作放入其日志中
replicas are a majority the replicas get
this new operation into their logs said
它被复制，然后当其领导者知道所有的副本
it is replicated and then when its
leader knows that all of the replicas of
仅当木筏向该钥匙发送备份通知时，才将此副本
a copy of this only then as a raft sent
a notification up back up to the key
珍惜他们在说啊哈，你发给我的手术我的意思是
value they are saying aha that operation
you sent me I mean
现在已将其提交到所有副本中，因此可以安全地复制
it's been now committed into all the
replicas and so it's safely replicated
此时，可以在筏子上执行该操作
and at this point it's okay to execute
that operation a raft you know the
客户端发送请求的键值层Q值层不
client sends a request with the key
value layer Q value layer does not
执行它，所以我们不确定，因为它只有在被复制时才被复制
execute it yet so we're not sure because
it hasn't been replicated only when it's
进出，所有副本的日志随后筏通知领导
in out and the logs of all the replicas
then raft notifies the leader now the
领导者实际执行与您知道的看跌期权相对应的操作
leader actually execute the operation
which corresponds to you know for a put
更新值，但仍从表中读取正确的值，然后最终
updating the value yet reading correct
value out of the table and then finally
将回复发送回客户端，这是它的常规操作
sends the reply back to the client so
that's the ordinary operation of it
提交，如果它是大多数，那么我不能全部成为的原因是
submitted if it's in a majority and
again the reason why I can't be all is
如果我们要构建一个容错系统，它必须能够
that if we want to build a
fault-tolerant system it has to be able
即使某些服务器出现故障也能取得进步，所以
to make progress even if some of the
server's have failed so yeah so ever
当它占多数时就承诺
it's committed when it's in a majority
[音乐]
[Music]
是的，另外，当操作最终提交每个副本时，
yeah and so in addition when operations
finally committed each of the replicas
将操作发送到每个筏库层
sends the operation up each of the raft
library layer sends the operation up to
本地应用程序层中的本地应用程序层将应用该操作
the local application layer in the local
application layer applies that operation
到它的状态到它的状态，所以他们都希望所有复制品看起来像
to its state its state and so they all
so hopefully all the replicas seem the
它们以相同的顺序出现在这些up呼叫中的相同操作流
same stream of operations they show up
in these up calls in the same order they
以相同的顺序应用于状态，并且您知道
get applied to the state in the same
order and you know assuming the
操作是确定性的，最好是副本的状态
operations are deterministic which they
better be the state of the replicas
复制状态将在所有副本上以相同的方式演化，因此
replicated State will evolve in
identically on all the replicas so
通常，此表是论文在讨论时要讨论的内容
typically this this table is what the
paper is talking about when it talks
关于陈述这种互动方式的另一种方式，
about state a different way of viewing
this interaction and one that'll sort of
在此过程中会出现很多符号是一种时间图
notation that will come up a lot in this
course is that a sort of time diagram
我将为您绘制消息工作原理的时间图，让我们假设我们有一个
I'll draw you a time diagram of how the
messages work so let's imagine we have a
客户和服务器一是领导者，我们也有服务器到服务器三，
client and server one is the leader that
we also have server to server three and
时间在此图上向下流动，我们想象客户端发送原始
time flows downward on this diagram we
imagine the client sending the original
在该服务器的筏层发送附加条目后，向服务器一请求
request to server one after that server
ones raft layer sends an append entries
RPC到两个副本的每一个，这只是普通的，我会说一个put请求
RPC to each of the two replicas this is
just an ordinary I'll say a put request
这是附加条目，请求服务器现在正在等待答复，并且
this is append entries requests the
server is now waiting for replies and
来自大多数副本的服务器会尽快从其他副本返回服务器
the server's from other replicas as soon
as replies from a majority arrive back
包括领导者本身，所以在一个只有三个左右的系统中，因为
including the leader itself so in a
system with only three about because the
领导者只需要等待另一个副本对一个
leader only has to wait for one other
replica to respond positively to an
一旦收集到多数人的正面回应，就追加条目
append entries as soon as it assembles
positive responses from a majority the
领导者执行命令找出什么
leader
execute a command figures out what the
答案就像忘记，然后将回复发送回客户端
answer is like forget
and sends the reply back to the client
我的意思是，为什么您当然知道如果某人实际上还活着，会发回
I mean why of course you know if s who's
actually awry alive it'll send back its
也有回应，但我们不必等待，尽管了解和
response too but we're not waiting for
it although it's useful to know and
图-好的每个人都看到这是一种普通的操作
figure - all right everybody see this
this is the sort of ordinary operation
系统无故障
of the system no no failures
哦天哪，是的，我喜欢我省略了重要的步骤，所以领导者您知道这一点
oh gosh yeah I like I left out important
steps so you know this point the leader
知道哦，我知道你知道我是adora没写在日志里，我可以继续
knows oh I got you know I'm adora t have
put it in no log I can go ahead and
执行它并向客户端回复是，因为它已提交但服务器2
execute it and reply yes to the client
because it's committed but server two
什么都不知道，只是知道你知道我收到了这个请求
doesn't know anything yet it just knows
well you know I got this request from
领导者，但我不知道它是否已经落实取决于
the leader but I don't know if it's
committed yet depends on for example
我的回复是否返回给所有服务器的领导者，知道它的回复是
whether my reply got back to the leader
for all server to knows it's reply was
由网络带来的领导者可能从未听过回复，也从未决定
brought by the network maybe the leader
never heard the reply and never decided
提交此请求，因此一旦服务器出现实际上还有另一个阶段
to commit this request so there's
actually another stage once the server
意识到提交了一个请求，然后需要告诉其他副本
realizes that a request is committed it
then needs to tell the other replicas
这个事实，所以有
that fact and so there are there's
这里有一条额外的消息，确切地说，该消息是多少取决于
there's an extra message here exactly
what that message is depends a little
至少在筏子上发生了什么，这是没有明确的
bit on what what else is going on it's
at least in raft there's not an explicit
提交消息，而不是将信息附加在下一个附录中
commit message instead the information
is piggybacked inside the next append
领导者发送下一个附加项的条目
entries that leader sends out the next
append entries RPC it sends out for
诸如有提交计量表提交之类的原因
whatever reason like there's a commit
meter commit or something filled in that
RPC和领导者下次需要发送心跳心跳或
RPC and the next time the leader needs
have to send a heartbeat heartbeat or
需要发出新的客户端请求，因为一些不同的客户端请求
needs to send out a new client request
because some different client requests
或它将发出新的雇用领导承诺价值的东西，
or something it'll send out the new hire
leader commit value and at that point
副本将执行该操作并将其应用于其状态yes
the replicas will execute the operation
and apply it to their state yes
哦，是的，所以这是一个协议，其中包含很多技巧
oh yes so this is a this is a protocol
that has a quite a bit of chitchat in it
而且它不是超级快，的确，您知道是的，客户端发送了请求请求，
and it's not super fast indeed you know
yeah client sends in request request has
要进入服务器，服务器与之对话，至少您知道另一个实例
to get to the server the server talks to
at least you know another instance that
多个消息必须等待响应发送回一些东西，所以
multiple messages has to wait for the
responses send something back so there's
一堆消息往返时间在这里嵌入
a bunch of message round-trip times kind
of embedded here
是的，如果是这样，这取决于您作为实施者的实际时间
yes if so this is up to you as the
implementer actually exactly when the
如果客户仅要求复出，领导者将发出更新的提交索引
leader sends out the updated commit
index if client requests a comeback only
有时候，您知道领导者可能想发出心跳
very occasionally then you know the
leader may want to send out a heartbeat
或发送特殊的追加条目消息（如果客户端请求相当多）
or send out a special append entries
message if client requests come quite
经常那么没关系，因为如果他们来了，你就会知道
frequently then it doesn't matter
because if they come you know there's
每秒到达一千，然后再快一点，很快就会成为另一个
thousand arrive per second and gee so
it'll be another one along very soon and
这样您就可以背负而不产生额外的消息
so you can piggyback so without
generating an extra message which is
有点贵，您可以在下一封邮件中获取信息
somewhat expensive you can get the
information out on the next message you
无论如何都会发送，实际上我不认为复制品的时间
were gonna send anyway in fact I I don't
think the time at which the replicas
执行该请求至关重要，因为至少在没有人等待的情况下，
execute the request is critical because
nobody's waiting for it at least if
如果没有失败副本执行请求，就不会失败
there's no failures if there's no
failures replicas executing the request
并没有真正走在关键路径上，就像客户不在等待他们一样
isn't really on the critical path like
the client isn't waiting for them the
客户看到我在等待领导者执行，所以可能不是
client saw me waiting for the leader to
execute so it may not be that it may not
影响客户感知到的延迟，确切地讲如何分阶段上演
affect client perceived latency sort of
exactly how this gets staged
好吧，你应该问的一个问题是为什么系统为什么系统如此
all right one question you should ask is
why does the system why is the system so
专注于博客，日志在做什么，这值得一试
focused on blogs what are the logs doing
and it's sort of worth trying to come up
一个明确的答案，一个答案，为什么系统是完全
with an explicit answers to that one
answer to why the system is totally
专注于日志的是日志是领导者通过的一种机制
focused on logs is that the log is the
kind of mechanism by which the leader
命令操作对于这些复制状态机至关重要，因为所有
orders operations it's vital for these
replicated state machines that all the
副本不仅将相同的客户端操作应用于开始，而且将相同
replicas apply not just the same client
operations to their start but the same
操作以相同的顺序进行，但它们都必须应用这些操作
operations in the same order but they
all have to apply that these operations
来自客户端的顺序相同，日志来自其他
coming from the clients in the same
order and the log among many other
事物是领导者或领导者通过其分配命令的机制的一部分
things is part of the machinery by which
the or the leader assigns an order to
我给您的传入客户端操作知道十个客户端将操作发送到
the incoming client operations I give
you know ten clients send operations to
领导者必须同时选择领导者的客户
the leader at the same time the client
the leader has to pick pick an order
确保所有人都遵守该命令，并且日志是您知道的
make sure everybody all the replicas
obey that order and the log is you know
日志在半米的一部分上标有编号的插槽这一事实表示
the fact that the log has numbered slots
as part of half a meter expresses the
顺序选择日志的另一种用途是在这一点和
order it's chosen another use of the log
is that between this point and this
点服务器3收到尚未确定已提交的操作，并且
point server 3 has received an operation
that it is not yet sure is committed and
它无法执行它，但必须将此操作放在某个地方，直到
it cannot execute it yet it has to put
the this operation aside somewhere until
引入领导者提交值的增量，等等，
the increment to the leader commit value
comes in and so another thing that the
日志所做的是，在关注者上，日志是关注者所在的地方
log is doing is that on the followers
the log is the place where the follower
暂时搁置但已经到来但仍保留的操作
sort of sets aside operations that are
still tentative that have arrived but
还不知道会犯下这些罪行，我们可能会把它们扔掉
are not yet known to be committed and
they may have to be thrown away as we'll
看到，这是另一种用途，我是领导者方面的一种爱
see so that's another use I'm the I sort
of do love that use on the leader side
领导者需要记住其日志中的操作，因为它可能
is that the leader needs to remember
operations in its log because it may
如果某些关注者离线，则需要将其转发给关注者
need to retransmit them to followers if
some followers offline maybe it's
网络短暂发生了一些事情
something briefly happened to its
network
动作或某些内容错过了领导者需要重新发送的某些消息
action or something misses some messages
the leader needs to be able to resend
记录任何追随者错过的消息，因此领导者需要一个地方
log messages that any followers missed
and so the leader needs a place where
可以预留客户端请求消息的副本，甚至是
can set aside copies of messages of
client requests even ones that it's
为了能够将它们重新发送给客户端，我已经执行了
already executed in order to be able to
resend them to the client I mean we send
将它们复制到错过了该操作的副本，这是所有原因的最终原因
them to replicas that missed missed that
operation and a final reason for all of
他们保留日志是至少在图2的世界中，如果有服务器
them to keep the log is that at least in
the world of figure 2 if a server
崩溃并重新启动，并希望重新加入，您真的需要，如果真的
crashes and restarts and wants to rejoin
and you really need if it you really
想要一台崩溃的服务器-实际上，我们启动并重新加入了Raft集群
want a server that crashes - in fact we
start and rejoin the raft cluster
否则，您现在只能使用三台服务器中的两台进行操作，
otherwise you're now operating with only
two out of three servers and you can't
能够承受更多的失败，我们需要重新整合失败并重新启动
survive any more failures we need to
reincorporate failed and rebooted
服务器，日志是服务器重新启动服务器在何处或使用什么日志
servers and the log is sort of where or
what a server rebooted server uses the
日志保留到其磁盘，因为其中一项规则是每个筏服务器需要
log persisted to its disk because one of
the rules is that each raft server needs
将其日志写入崩溃后仍将保留在其磁盘中的磁盘，
to write its log to its disk where it
will still be after it crashes and
重新启动该日志是服务器使用或重放该日志中的操作
restarts that log is what the server
uses or replays the operations in that
从头开始记录日志，以创建其崩溃时的状态，然后
log from the beginning to sort of create
its state as of when it crashed and then
然后从那里继续进行，因此日志也用作持久性的一部分
then it carries on from there so the log
is also used as part of the persistence
规划为一系列命令以重建状态
plan as a sequence of commands to
rebuild the state
最终好吧，所以问题在于领导者有能力
well ultimately okay so the question is
suppose the leader is capable of
每秒执行一千个客户端命令，并且仅跟随者
executing a thousand client commands a
second and the followers are only
不能每秒执行一百个客户端命令
incapable of executing a hundred client
commands per second that's sort of
持续速率，您知道全速v，因此需要注意的一件事是
sustained rate you know full speed v so
one thing to note is that the the
复制追随者在执行命令之前确认命令，因此
replicas the followers acknowledge
commands before they execute them so
他们交配的速度是他们承认并在日志中积累的东西
they mate rate at which they acknowledge
and accumulate stuff in their logs is
不受限制，所以您知道他们可以承认每千个请求
not limited so you know maybe they can
acknowledge that a thousand requests per
如果他们永远这样做，那么他们将建立无限大小的日志
second if they do that forever then they
will build up unbounded size logs
因为他们的执行率下降，它将落在后面
because their execution rate falls it
will fall on an unbounded amount behind
领导者根据以下规则提供信息的速率
the rate at which the leader has given
the messages sort of under the rules of
我们的游戏，这意味着它们最终将在以下位置耗尽内存
our game and so what that means they
will eventually run out of memory at
因此，在他们拥有十亿个日志条目之后，他们拥有十亿个条目
some point so after they have a billion
after they fall a billion log entries
就像它们将调用内存分配器为新的空间一样
behind those just like they'll call the
memory allocator for space for a new
博客条目，它将失败，所以是的，Raph没Raph没有流程
blog entry and it will fail so yeah and
Raph doesn't Raph doesn't have the flow
控件来解决这个问题，所以我认为在实际系统中
controls that's required to cope with
this so I think in a real system you
实际上需要您知道您可能piggy带了，并且不需要
would actually need you know probably
piggybacked and doesn't need to be
实时，但您可能需要在此处进行某种形式的附加通信
real-time but you probably need some
kind of additional communication here
那很好，这就是我已经执行了多远，所以领导者
that says well here's how far I've
gotten in execution so that the leader
可以说，您知道在此之前有成千上万的请求
can say well you know too many thousands
of requests ahead of the point in which
追随者已经处决，是的，我想你可能知道
the followers have executed yes I think
there's probably you know in a
您想要将生产系统推向最大极限的生产系统
production system that you're trying to
push to the absolute max you would you
如果距离太远，可能很需要额外的消息来限制领导者
might well need an extra message to
throttle the leader if it got too far
先
ahead
好的，所以问题是这些服务器之一是否崩溃了，是否有此日志
okay so the question is if if one of
these servers crashes it has this log
之所以坚持到磁盘，是因为它是图2的规则之一，所以
that it persisted to disk because that's
one of the rules of figure two so the
服务器将只能从磁盘重新登录，但是该服务器当然
server will be able to be just logged
back from disk but of course that server
不知道执行日志要走多远，也不知道
doesn't know how far it got in executing
the log and also it doesn't know at
至少当它第一次按照图2的规则重新启动时，它甚至不知道如何
least when it first reboots by the rule
that figure two it doesn't even know how
许多日志已提交，因此您问题的第一个答案是
much of the log is committed so the
first answer to your question is that
重新启动后，您立即知道服务器崩溃并重新启动，并且
immediately after a restart you know
after a server crashes and restarts and
读取其日志，因此不允许对其执行任何操作，因为它确实
reads its log it is not allowed to do
anything with the log because it does
不知道系统已经在日志中提交了多长时间
not know how far the system has
committed in its log maybe as long as
它的所有注释都有一千个未提交的条目，零个已提交的条目
has a thousand uncommitted entries and
zero committed entries for all it notes
所以
so
这是一种领先的染料支持，也无济于事，但让我们假设他们已经
it's a leader dye support that doesn't
help either but let's suppose they've
所有人都崩溃了，这已经超越了我，但是很好
all crashed this is getting ahead of its
getting a bit ahead of me but well
假设他们都崩溃了，所以他们所拥有的只是被标记的状态
suppose they've all crashed and so all
they have is the state that was marked
在图2中是非易失性的，其中包括日志和最新的
as non-volatile in figure 2 which
includes the log and maybe the latest
学期，所以他们不知道是否发生了车祸，但他们都崩溃了，
term and so they don't know some if
there's a crash but they all crash and
他们总是开始，他们都不知道起初他们走了多远
they always start none of them knows
initially how far they had been have
在崩溃之前执行，所以发生的事情是你领导选举
executed before the crash so what
happens is that you leader election one
他们中的一个被选为领导者，而如果您通过某种方式跟踪
of them gets picked as a leader and that
leader if you sort of track through what
图2说明了Rees吊坠应该如何工作，领导者将
figure 2 says about how a pendant Rees
is supposed to work the leader will
实际算是发出吊坠或发出吊坠的副产品
actually figure out as a byproduct of
sending out a pendant or sending out the
第一次心跳真的是假的，它将弄清楚最新的意义是什么
first heartbeat really it'll fake it'll
figure out what the latest point is
基本上，大多数复制品都同意
basically that that all of the that a
majority of the replicas agree on their
法律，因为那是承诺点，另一种看待它的方式是，
laws because that's the commit point
another way of looking at it is that
通过附加条目机制选择领导者后，领导者
once you choose a leader through the
append entries mechanism the leader
强制所有其他副本对领导者拥有相同的日志，并且
forces all of the other replicas to have
identical logs to the leader and at that
这一点加上论文的一些额外说明，因为
point plus a little bit of extra the
paper explains at that point since the
领导者知道这迫使所有副本拥有它，而我没有日志
leader knows that it's forced all the
replicas to have it I didn't have logs
与它完全相同，那么它知道所有副本还必须具有一个
that are identicals to it then it knows
that all the replicas must also have a
必须有大多数复制品，其中所有这些原木受伤
there must be a majority of replicas
with that all those log injuries in that
现在必须相同的日志也必须提交，因为它们已保存
logs which are now are identical must
also be committed because they're held
在大多数副本上，那时领导者就知道
on a majority of replicas and at that
point a leader you know the append
图2中描述的领导者条目代码将增加领导者
entries code described in Figure 2 for
the leader will increment the leaders
提交点，现在每个人都可以从
commit point and everybody can now
execute the entire log from the
从头开始并重新建立他们的状态，可能非常费力
beginning and recreate their state from
scratch possibly extremely laborious Lee
这就是图二所说的，显然这是从头开始执行的
so that's what figure two says it's
obviously this be executing from scratch
不是很吸引人，但是它是基本协议的所在，我们将看到
is not very attractive but it's where
the basic protocol does and we'll see
明天，这种版本的版本将更有效地用作
tomorrow that the the sort of version of
this is more efficient to use as
检查站，我们明天再谈，好吧，这是
checkpoints and we'll talk about
tomorrow okay so this was a sequence in
一种普通的非故障操作
sort of ordinary non failure operation
我想简要提及的另一件事是该界面看起来像您
another thing I want to briefly mention
is what this interface looks like you've
由于在实验室工作，可能所有人都看到了一点，但大致
probably all seen a little bit of it due
to working on the labs but roughly
如果您要说说这个键值层及其状态和
speaking if you have let's say that this
key value layer with its state and the
底下的木筏层每个副本上确实有两个主要部分
raft layer underneath it there's on each
replica there's really two main pieces
它们之间的接口的键值层使用这种方法
of the interface between them there's
this method by which the key value layer
如果客户端发送请求，则可以中继键值层必须将其交给
can relay if a client sends in a request
the key value layer has to give it to
包装并说请您知道将此请求放入日志中的某个位置，然后
wrap and say please you know fit this
request into the log somewhere and
那是您在Raph go中看到的开始功能，实际上只需要一个
that's the start function that you'll
see in Raph go and really just takes one
争论客户命令他们说的关键值，请给我
argument the client command the key
value they're saying please I got this
命令进入日志，并告诉我何时提交日志以及其他内容
command to get into the log and tell me
when it's committed and the other piece
界面的是筏层通过by会通知键值
of the interface is that by and by the
raft layer will notify the key value
您在启动命令中向我发送的AHA操作层
layer that AHA that operation that you
sent to me in a start command a while
以前，这可能不是最近的开始，您知道
ago which may well not be the most
recent start right there you know a
一百个客户端命令可能会进入，并导致在任何以下命令之前开始调用
hundred client commands could come in
and cause calls to start before any of
他们做出了这样的承诺，并通过这种向上的沟通采取了形式
them are committed so by and by this
upward communication is takes the form
筏库发送的go通道上的消息的种类和键值
of a message on a go channel that the
raft library sends on and key value
层应该从中读取，所以有一个称为Apply的apply
layer is supposed to read from so
there's this apply called the apply
频道并在其上发送申请消息
channel and on it on it you send apply
message
这个开始，当然您需要键值层能够
this start and of course you need the
the key value layer needs to be able to
匹配消息，该消息接收到带有发起该呼叫的呼叫的应用频道
match up message that receives an apply
channel with calls to start that it made
因此start命令实际上返回了足够的信息
and so the start command actually
returns enough information for that
发生匹配，它返回启动函数基本上返回的索引
matchup to happen it returns the index
that start functions basically returns
日志中的索引（如果此命令已提交，则该索引可能未提交）
the index in the log where if this
command is committed which it might not
它将在该索引上提交，我认为它也会返回当前词条
be it'll be committed at this index and
I think it also returns the current term
还有一些其他我们不太在乎的东西，那么这个应用信息就是
and some other stuff we don't care about
very much and then this apply message is
将包含index命令，并且所有副本都将应用这些副本
going to contain the index command and
all the replicas will get these apply
消息，所以他们都会知道，尽管我应该将此命令弄清楚
messages so they'll all know though I
should apply this command figure out
该命令的含义并将其应用到我的当地州，他们也得到了
what this command means and apply it to
my local State and they also get the
索引索引实际上仅对我有用，我是领导者，因此它可以弄清楚
index the index is really only useful
I'm the leader so it can figure out what
客户会谈论客户的要求
client would what client requests were
talking about
通过
by
答案是一个稍有不同的问题，让我们假设客户端发送了
the answer a slightly different question
let's suppose the client sends any
让我们说这是一个看跌期权或一个看跌期权，或者实际上不是
request in let's say it's a put or a get
could be put or again it doesn't really
我要说的是要让客户明白这一点
matter I'd say it to get the point in
which the it's a client sense and again
并等待响应，领导者将在以下时间发送响应
and waits for a response the point at
which the leader will send a response at
一切都是在领导者知道命令已提交之后，所以这将
all is after the leader knows that
command is committed so this is going to
是一种获得回复的方法，这样客户就看不到我的意思了，所以
be a sort of get reply so the client
doesn't see anything back I mean and so
就实际软件堆栈而言，这意味着密钥
that means in terms of the actual
software stack that means that the key
值RPC将到达键值层将调用start函数
value the RPC will arrive the key value
layer will call the start function the
启动功能将返回到键值层，但键值层将
start function will return to the key
value layer but the key value layer will
尚未回复客户，因为它实际上不知道是否很好
not yet reply to the client because it
does not know if it's good actually it
现在还没有执行客户的请求，甚至都不知道是否会
hasn't executed the clients request now
it doesn't even know if it ever will
因为不确定该请求是否会在
because it's not sure if the request is
going to be committed right in the
可能不会提交的情况是您知道的键值层是否在猜测
situation which may not be committed is
if the key value layer you know guess
请求调用开始，右舷右转两次后立即崩溃
the request calls start and immediately
after starboard turn two crashes right
当然还没有发出应用附加消息或其他内容的信息
certainly hasn't sent out its apply what
append messages or whatever
是的，什么也不做，所以游戏是开始返回时间过去了
nothing's be committed yep so so the
game is start returns time passes the
与该客户请求相对应的相关应用消息出现在密钥上
relevant apply message corresponding to
that client request appears to the key
值服务器仅在应用通道上，然后才导致键值
value server on the apply channel and
only then and that causes the key value
服务器执行请求并将其发送给她
server to execute the request and send
her a plot
这就像当一切都不重要时，这一切非常重要
and that's like all this is very
important when it doesn't really matter
如果一切顺利，但如果失败了，我们现在就到了
if all everything goes well but if
there's a failure we're now at the point
我们开始担心剧院的地方我的意思是对那里非常感兴趣
where we start worrying about theatres I
mean extremely interested in if there
失败了，客户看到了什么
was a failure what did the client see
好的，所以一件事就是你们所有人都应该
all right and so one thing that does
come up is that all of you should be
至少对此一开始就很熟悉
familiar with this that at least
initially one interesting thing about
日志是它们可能不相同，有一堆
the logs is that they may not be
identical there are a whole bunch of
至少在短时间内结束的情况
situations in which at least for brief
periods of time the ends of the
不同的副本日志可能会有所不同，例如，如果领导者开始发送
different replicas logs may diverge like
for example if a leader starts to send
发出一轮附加消息，但是在发送所有消息之前崩溃
out a round of append messages but
crashes before it's able to send all
他们出来，你知道那意味着获得附件的一些副本
them out you know that'll mean that some
of the replicas that got the append
消息将追加，您知道新的日志条目和未获得的日志条目
message will append you know that new
log entry and the ones that didn't get
附加消息RPC不会附加它们，因此很容易看到
that append messages RPC won't have
appended them so it's easy to see that
日志是我有时会发散的好消息是木筏的方式
the logs are I'm gonna diverge sometimes
the good news is that the the way a raft
工作实际上最终迫使日志在一段时间后变得相同
works actually ends up forcing the logs
to be identical after a while there may
是暂时的差异，但从长远来看，所有日志都将是
be transient differences but in the long
run all the logs will sort of be
由领导者修改，直到领导者保险公司都完全相同，然后
modified by the leader until the leader
insurers are all identical and only then
他们执行得还好吗，所以我认为接下来确实有两个大话题
are they executed okay so I think the
next there's really two big topics to
在这里谈论筏一是领导者选举的工作原理，这是实验二
talk about here for raft one is how
leader election works which is lab two
另一个是领导者如何处理不同的副本日志
and the other is how the leader deals
with the different replicas logs
特别是失败之后，所以首先我想谈谈领导人选举
particularly after failure so first I
want to talk about leader election
要问的问题是系统为什么甚至有领导者，为什么我们需要一个
question to ask is how come the system
even has a leader why do we need a
领导者答案的一部分是您不需要领导者来构建像
leader the part of the answer is you do
not need a leader to build a system like
这样您就可以建立一个协议系统，通过该协议系统
this you it is possible to build an
agreement system by which a cluster of
服务器同意您知道日志中的条目顺序，而没有任何种类
servers agrees you know the sequence of
entries in a log without having any kind
指定领导者的确是原始包装系统
of designated leader
and indeed the original pack so system
该文件指出原始Paxos没有领导者，因此有可能
which the paper refers to original Paxos
did not have a leader so it's possible
木筏之所以有领导者，基本上是因为
the reason why raft has a leader is
basically that there's probably a lot of
原因，但最重要的原因之一是您可以构建更高效的
reasons but one of the foremost reasons
is that you can build a more efficient
在服务器不出现故障的常见情况下，可以构建更多的服务器
in the common case in which the server's
don't fail it's possible to build a more
有效的系统，如果您有领导者，因为有指定的领导者
efficient system if you have a leader
because with a designated leader
每个人都知道领导者是谁，您基本上可以就要求达成协议
everybody knows who the leader is you
can basically get agreement on requests
作为每个系统的负责人，每个请求只有一轮消息
that with one round of messages per
request where as leader of this systems
拥有更多的风味，您需要进行第一轮谈判才能达成共识
have more of the flavor of well you need
a first round to kind of agree on a
临时负责人，然后进行第二轮实际发出请求，因此
temporary leader and then a second round
actually send out the requests so it's
现在使用领导者的情况可能使系统速度提高了两倍
probably the case that use of a leader
now speeds up the system by a factor two
而且也使人们更容易思考筏上发生的事情
and it also makes it sort of easier to
think about what's going on raft goes
通过一系列领导者，它使用这些术语编号来进行排序
through a sequence of leaders and it
uses these term numbers in order to sort
歧义的我们正在谈论的那个领导者原来
of disambiguate which leader we're
talking about it turns out that
追随者真的不需要知道他们真正的领导者的身份
followers don't really need to know the
identity of the leader they really just
需要知道当前术语号是每个术语最多有一个
need to know what the current term
number is each term has at most one
领导者，这是您每个学期都知道的重要财产
leader that's a critical property you
know for every term there might be no
在那个任期内的领导者，或者可能有一个领导者，但不能有两个
leader during that term or there might
be one leader but there cannot be two
在同一任期的领导者中，每个任期都必须有最多一位领导者
leaders during the same term every term
has it must most one leader how do the
领导者首先被创造出来，每个木筏服务器都保持着这次选举
leaders get created in the first place
every raft server keeps this election
计时器，这只是一个时间，它基本上只是记录下来的时间而已
timer which is just a it's basically
just out of time that it has recorded
那很好，如果那个时间发生，我将要做某事
that says well if that time occurs I'm
going to do something and the something
的确是，如果整个领导人选举期满而没有
that it does is that if an entire leader
election period expires without the
服务器听到当前领导者的任何消息，然后服务器
server having heard any message from the
current leader then the server sort of
假设当前领导者已经去世并开始选举，那么我们
assumes probably that the current leader
is dead and starts an election so we
有这个选举计时器
have this election timer
如果到期，我们开始选举
and if it expires we start an election
而开始选举的意思基本上是您增加任期
and what it means to start an election
is basically that you increment the term
将服务器确定为候选服务器的候选服务器，
the the candidate the server that's
decided it's going to be a candidate and
一种新的选举首先增加了这个任期，因为它想要
sort of force a new election first
increments this term because it wants
他们要成为新的领导者，本身就是领导者，你知道领导者一个词不能
them to be a new leader namely itself
and you know leader a term can't have
不止一位领导者，所以我们必须开始新的任期才能拥有新的领导者
more than one leader so we got to start
a new term in order to have a new leader
然后发出这些请求，船是我要发送的豌豆种子
and then it sends out these requests
boats are pea seeds I'm going to send
发出一轮完整的请求票，您可能只需要发送n减
out a full round of request votes and
you may only have to send out n minus
一个人要求投票，因为其中一项规则是，新候选人总是
one requests votes because one of the
rules is that a new candidate always
在选举中为自己投票，因此要注意的一件事是
votes for itself in the election so one
thing to note about this is that it's
如果领导者没有失败，我们就不会进行选举
not quite the case that if the leader
didn't fail we won't have an election
但是如果领导者确实失败了，那么我们将以任何
but if the leader does fail then we will
have election an election assuming any
其他服务器启动，因为有一天其他服务器选举计时器走了
other server is up because some day the
other servers election timers go will go
离开，但由于领导者没有失败，我们可能仍会不幸举行选举，因此
off but as leader didn't fail we might
still unfortunately get an election so
如果网络速度慢或出现一些心跳或某些问题，我们可能最终会失败
if the network is slow or drops a few
heartbeats or something we may end up
即使有一个非常好的领导者，选举计时器也会关闭
having election timers go off and even
though there was a perfectly good leader
尽管如此，我们可能还是要进行新的选举，所以我们必须牢记这一点
we may nevertheless have a new election
so we have to sort of keep that in mind
当我们在考虑正确性及其含义时
when we're thinking about the
correctness and what that in turn means
就是如果有新的选举，很可能旧的情况
is that if there's a new election it
could easily be the case that the old
领导者仍然闲逛，仍然认为这是领导者，好像
leader is still hanging around and still
thinks it's the leader like if there's a
例如，网络分区，旧的领导者仍然活着，并且在
network partition for example and the
old leader is still alive and well in a
少数党派多数党派可能进行选举，实际上
minority partition the majority
partition may run an election and indeed
一次成功的选举并选择一位新领导人，而这一切都是未知的
a successful election and choose a new
leader all totally unknown to the
以前的领导者，所以我们也必须担心您知道那是什么
previous leader so we also have to worry
about you know what's that previous
领导人会这样做，因为它不知道会有新的选举
leader gonna do since it does not know
there was a new election yes
好的，所以问题是，是否会有病理情况
okay so the question is are there can
there be pathological cases in which for
单向网络通信示例可能会阻止系统
example one-way network communication
can prevent the system from making
进展，我相信答案肯定是肯定的，例如，如果当前
progress I believe the answer is yes
certainly so for example if the current
如果其网络由于某种原因导致一半失败，则当前领导者可以发送出去
leader if its network somehow half fails
in a way the current leader can send out
心跳，但无法接收任何客户端请求
heartbeats
but can't receive any client requests
那么它发出的心跳就会传递出来，因为
then the heartbeats that it sends out
which are delivered because it's
传出网络连接正常工作，其传出心跳将抑制任何
outgoing network connection works its
outgoing heartbeats will suppress any
从其他服务器开始选举，但事实是它是传入网络
other server from starting an election
but the fact that it's incoming Network
为什么或显然被破坏将阻止它听到并执行任何客户
why or apparently is broken will prevent
it from hearing and executing any client
命令，这绝对是筏不能抵抗各种威胁的情况
commands it's absolutely the case that
raft is not proof against all sort of
可能出现的所有疯狂的网络问题我相信我已经想到的问题
all crazy Network problems that can come
up I believe the ones I've thought about
我认为可以解决这个问题，因为我们可以通过
I believe are fixable in the sense that
the we could solve this one by having a
需要一种双向心跳，如果领导者发出心跳
sort of requiring a two-way heartbeat in
which if the leader sends out heartbeats
但是您知道有些人需要在其中回复
but you know there were in which
followers are required to reply in some
心跳的方式我想如果领导者已经要求应用它们
way to heartbeats I guess they are
already required to apply if the leader
一段时间之后，停止查看对其心跳的回复，并且
stop seeing replies to its heartbeats
then after some amount of time and which
是季节决定，领导者决定辞职我觉得那很具体
is seasonals replies the leader decides
to step down I feel like that specific
这个问题可以解决，许多其他问题也可以解决，但是我但是你知道你是绝对的
issue can be fixed and many others can
too but I but you know you're absolutely
对，网络中可能会发生非常奇怪的事情，包括一些
right that very strange things can
happen to networks including some that
该协议没有准备好
the protocol is not prepared for
好，所以我们进行了这些电表选择，我们需要确保最多
okay so we got these meter elections we
need to ensure that there is at most at
每学期最多一米Rath如何做到这一点Rath要求
most one meter per term
how does Rath do that well Rath requires
为了当选一职，筏需要候选人获得赞成票
in order to be elected for a term Raft
requires a candidate to get yes votes
从大多数服务器的服务器中提取，并且每个服务器只会
from a majority of the server's the
servers and each server will only cast
每学期一次赞成票，因此在任何给定学期中，您基本上都知道
one yes vote per term so in any given
term you know it basically means that in
任何给定学期的复活节只对你没有的一个候选人投票一次
any given term Easter votes only once
for only one candidate you can't have
两个候选人都获得多数票，因为每个人只能投票一次
two candidates both get a majority of
votes because everybody votes only once
所以多数人多数统治导致最多有一场胜利
so the majorities majority rule causes
there to be at most one winning
候选人，那么我们每回合最多选举一名候选人
candidate and so then we get at most one
candidate elected per turn
另外，至关重要的是，多数原则意味着您甚至可以当选
and in addition critically the majority
rule means that you can get elected even
如果某些服务器崩溃了如果不是少数服务器崩溃了
if some servers have crashed right if a
minority of servers are crashed aren't
可用和网络问题，如果超过一半
available and network problems we can
still elect a leader if more than half a
崩溃或不可用或在另一个分区中或实际上然后
crash or not available or in another
partition or something then actually the
系统只会坐在那里一次又一次地选举一位领导者，从不
system will just sit there trying again
and again to elect a leader and never
如果实际上不能选出一台不占多数的实时服务器，则选择一个
elect one if it cannot in fact they're
not a majority of live servers if an
选举成功，如果每个人都了解我，那么每个人都会很棒
election succeeds everybody would be
great if everybody learned about it I
意思是需要问自己所有各方如何学习了解发生了什么
mean need to ask ourselves how do all
the parties learn learn what happened
赢得选举的服务器（假设它不会使服务器崩溃）
the server that wins an election
assuming it doesn't crash the server
赢得选举的人实际上将获得多数或赞成票
that wins election will actually see a
majority or positive votes for its
请求其他大多数服务器的投票，以便候选人运行
request vote from a majority of the
other servers so the candidates running
赢得选举的选举赢得选举的肯尼迪实际上将
the election that wins it the Kennedy
that wins the election will actually
直接知道呃我获得了大多数选票，但是没有其他人直接知道谁
know directly uh I got a majority of
votes but nobody else directly knows who
获胜者是或是否有人，候选人以这种方式告知其他人
the winner was or whether anybody one so
the way that the candidate informs other
服务器是心跳的规则和数字，如果您在
servers is that heartbeat the rules and
figure to say oh if you're in an
选举您立即要求发送独立
election your immediately required to
send out an independent
现在将所有其他服务器的树添加到心跳附加的附加条目
trees to all the other servers now the
append entries that heartbeat append
条目没有明确表示我赢得了大选，你知道我是任期的领导者
entries doesn't explicitly say I won the
election you know I'm a leader for term
23它比信息的方式更微妙
23 it's a little more subtle than that
the the way the information is
传达的是除非允许任何人发送附加条目，否则
communicated is that no one is allowed
to send out an append entries unless
他们是那个学期的领导者，所以我是一个事实，你知道我是一个服务器
they're a leader for that term so the
fact that I I'm a you know I'm a server
我看到哦，有一个选举要选举第19届，然后我渐渐发送了
and I saw oh there's an election for
term 19 and then by-and-by I sent an
附加词条为19的条目，告诉我我不知道谁
append entries whose term is 19 that
tells me that somebody I don't know who
但是有人赢得了选举，所以其他服务器才知道他们是
but somebody won the election so that's
how the other servers knows they were
接收该词的附加条目，并且该附加条目还具有
receiving append entries for that term
and that append entries also has the
重置领导者选举时间的效果，只要领导者是
effect of resetting everybody's election
time timer so as long as the leader is
并发出心跳消息或附加条目，至少您知道
up and it sends out heartbeat messages
or append entries at least you know at
服务器每次收到附加条目时应采用的速率
the rate that's supposed to every time a
server receives an append entries it'll
重置其选择计时器，并抑制任何人成为新手
reset its selection timer and sort of
suppress anybody from being a new
只要一切正常，重复的心跳就会
candidate so as long as everything's
functioning the repeated heartbeats will
当然可以防止任何进一步的选举，如果网络出现故障或数据包
prevent any further elections of course
it the network fails or packets are
仍然有可能举行选举，但如果一切顺利，我们会
dropped there may nevertheless be an
election but if all goes well we're sort
不太可能会举行选举，因为该计划可能会失败
of unlikely to get an election this
scheme could fail in the sense that it
不能以公平的方式选举领导人，但可以以失败告终。
can't fail in the sense of electing to
leaders fair term but it can fail in the
选一个零领导者这个词可能有点早
sense of electing zero leaders for a
term that's sort of morningway it may
失败的原因是，如果有太多服务器出现故障或不可用，或者网络故障
fail is that if too many servers are
dead or unavailable or a bad network
连接，因此，如果您无法聚集多数，则一无所获
connection so if you can't assemble a
majority you can't be elected nothing
发生选举失败的更有趣的方式是
happens the more interesting way in
which an election can fail is if
大家都来了，你知道没有失败没有丢包，只有两个
everybody's up you know there's no
failures no packets are dropped but two
领导人成为候选人的时间足够近，他们可以分开投票
leaders become candidate close together
enough in time that they split the vote
他们之间或说三个领导人
between them or say three leaders
所以假设我们有三升，假设我们有三个复制系统
so supposing we have three liters
supposing we have a three replica system
所有服务器的选举计时器都在同一时间关闭
all their election timers go off at the
same time every server both for itself
然后当他们每个人收到来自另一台服务器的请求投票时
and then when each of them receives a
request vote from another server well
它已经为自己投了票，所以说不，这意味着它
it's already cast its vote for itself
and so it says no so that means that it
服务器的所有三个需求都需要获得一票，每个人都不会获得多数票，
all three of the server's needs to get
one vote each nobody gets a majority and
没有人当选，因此他们的选举计时器将再次关闭，因为
nobody's elected so then their election
timers will go off again because the
仅当选举计时器获得附加条目但没有领导者时才说
election timers only be said if it gets
an append entries but there's no leader
因此，没有任何附加条目，它们都将再次具有其选举计时器，
so no append entries they'll all have
their election timers go off again and
如果我们不幸的话，他们都会在同一时间消失
if we're unlucky
they'll all go off at the same time
他们都会全力以赴，没人会获得多数，所以我很清楚
they'll all go for themselves nobody
will get a majority so so clearly I'm
确保大家都知道这一点，还有更多的故事和方式
sure you're all aware at this point
there's more to this story and the way
木筏使得这种分裂投票的可能性变得不可能但并非不可能
Raft makes this possibility of split
votes unlikely but not impossible
是通过随机化这些选举计时器来进行思考的方式以及
is by randomizing these election timers
so the way to think of it and the
随机化的思考方式是假设您有一些时间表
randomization the way to think of it is
that supposing you have some time line
我要在每个人都收到
I'm gonna draw a vents on there's some
point at which everybody received the
最后追加条目正确，然后服务器可能死了，我们假设
last append entries right and then maybe
the server died let's just assume the
服务器发出最后的心跳信号，然后死亡，所有追随者
server send out a last heartbeat and
then died well all of the followers have
这是我们在他们同时收到选举计时器时设置的，因为
this we set their election timers when
they received at the same time because
他们可能都在重置的同时都收到了这个附录
they probably all receive this append
enters at the same time they all reset
他们的选举计时器在将来的某个时候，但他们选择了
their election timers for some point in
the future the future but they chose
将来会有不同的随机时间，然后我们将离开
different random times in the future
which then we're gonna go off
因此，假设死者领导服务器一，现在服务器二和服务器三
so it's suppose the dead leader server
one so now server two and server 3 at
这一点将他们的选举计时器设置为将来的随机点
this point set their election timers for
a random point in the future let's say
服务器将其设置为我喜欢的计时器在这里关闭，服务器3将其设置为
server to set their I like some timer to
go off here and server 3 set its
选举计时器去那里，关于这张图片的关键点是
election timer to go off there and the
crucial point about this picture is that
假设他们选择了不同的随机数，其中一个是第一个
assuming they picked different random
numbers one of them is first and the
另一个是第二个权利，这是这里正在发生的事情，而第一个是第一个
other one is second right that's what's
going on here and the one that's first
假设这个差距足够大
assuming
this gap is big enough the one that's
首先，选举时间将先于其他选举开始
first it's election time will go off
first before the other ones election
计时器，如果我们很近的话，倒霉
timer and if we're close were not
unlucky
它有时间发送一整轮投票请求并从中获取答案
it'll have time to send out a full round
of vote requests and get answers from
在第二次选举计时器之前还活着的所有人
everybody who everybody's alive before
the second election timer goes off from
任何其他服务器，每个人都看到随机化D如何同步
any other server so does everybody see
how the randomization D synchronizes
不幸的是，这些候选人在设置内容方面有些技巧
these candidates unfortunately there's a
bit of art in setting the contents
这些选举计时器的常量存在某种竞争
constants for these election timers
there's some sort of competing
您可能要满足的要求，所以一个显而易见的要求是
requirements you might want to fulfill
so one obvious requirement is that the
选举计时器必须至少与预期的间隔时间相同
election timer has to be at least as
long as the expected interval between
心跳，你知道这很明显
heartbeats
you know this is pretty obvious that the
领导者每隔一百毫秒发出一次心跳
leader sends out heartbeats every
hundred milliseconds you better make
确保没有选举时间或任何人的选举时间是没有意义的
sure there's no point in having the
election time or anybody's election time
或曾经离开Borja 100毫秒，因为那样的话它将消失
or ever go off Borja for 100
milliseconds because then it will go off
在确定下限之前，下限是一个心跳间隔
before the lower limit is certainly the
lower limit is one heartbeat interval in
事实上，因为网络可能会丢弃数据包，所以您可能希望拥有
fact because the network may drop
packets you probably want to have the
最小选举计时器值是心跳间隔的几倍，所以400
minimum election timer value be a couple
of times the heartbeat interval so 400
您可能想要最短的毫秒心跳
millisecond heartbeats you probably want
to have the very shortest possible
选举时间，或者说300毫秒，您知道的三倍
election time or be you know say 300
milliseconds you know three times the
心跳间隔，这是最小的心跳，所以这
heartbeat interval so that's the sort of
minimum is the heart heartbeat so this
经常你想要最低限度是你知道两次或多次
frequent you want the minimum to be you
know a couple of times that or here so
你知道你将要均匀地随机分配的最大值
what about the maximum you know you're
gonna presumably randomize uniformly
在某些时间范围内，您知道我们应该在哪里设置最大时间
over some range of times you know where
should we set the kind of maximum time
我们在这里随机考虑了一些注意事项
that we're randomizing over there's a
couple of considerations here in a real
您知道这个最大时间影响系统从系统中恢复的速度
system you know this maximum time effect
how quickly the system can recover from
发生故障，因为请记住从服务器发生故障的时间到
failure because remember from the time
at which the server fails until the
第一次选举计时器关闭整个系统被冻结，没有领导者
first election timer goes off the whole
system is frozen there's no leader you
知道客户的要求被抛弃了，因为没有领导者
know the clients requests are being
thrown away because there's no leader
即使您大概知道这些，我们也不会分配新的领导者
and we're not assigning a new leader
even though you know presumably these
其他服务器已启动，因此我们选择此最大啤酒时间长短或延迟
other servers are up so the beer we
choose this maximum the long or delay
我们在恢复发生之前强加给客户端，您知道这是否是
we're imposing on clients before
recovery occurs you know whether that's
重要程度取决于我们需要达到何种高性能以及如何
important depends on sort of how high
performance we need this to be and how
通常我们认为每年都会发生一次失败。
often we think there will be failures
failures happen once a year then who
关心我们经常期望失败
cares
we're expecting failures frequently we
可能会非常在乎恢复还需要多长时间，所以这是一个考虑因素
may care very much how long it takes to
recover okay so that's one consideration
另一个考虑因素是，这个差距就是预期的时间间隔
the other consideration is that this gap
that is the expected gap in time between
第一次消失了，第二个定时器确实消除了这个差距
the first time are going off and the
second timer going off this gap really
为了有用，必须比候选人花费的时间更长
in order to be useful has to be longer
than the time it takes for the candidate
收集比预期的往返时间更长的所有人的选票
to assemble votes from everybody that is
longer than the expected round-trip time
发送RPC并获得响应所花费的时间，所以也许
the amount of time it takes to send an
RPC and get the response and so maybe it
需要10毫秒来发送RPC并从所有
takes 10 milliseconds to send an RPC and
get a response a response from all the
其他服务器，如果是这种情况，我们需要使最大长度至少更长
other servers and if that's the case we
need to make maximum at least long
足以使两者之间相差10毫秒
enough that there's pretty likely to be
10 milliseconds difference between the
最小随机数和第二个最小随机数
smallest random number and the next
smallest random number
如果您不从测试中恢复，对您来说，测试代码就会感到沮丧
and for you the test code will get upset
if you if you don't recover from a
领导者故障在几秒钟之内，因此，务实地需要调整
leader failure in a couple seconds and
so just pragmatically you need to tune
此最大值降低，因此很有可能您可以完成
this maximum down so that it's highly
likely that you'll be able to complete a
几秒钟之内的领导人选举，但这并不是一个非常严格的限制
leader election within a few seconds but
that's not a very tight constraint any
有关选举超时的问题，一个小问题是您想
questions about the election time outs
one tiny point is that you want to
每当我每次结点时都选择新的随机超时
choose new random time outs every time
there's every time you every time I node
将其设置为像我一样设置其选举计时器，即不要随机选择
sets it to like me sets its election
timer that is don't choose a random
第一次创建服务器时使用的编号，然后我们使用相同的编号
number when the server is first created
and then we use that same number over
一遍又一遍，因为您做出的不幸选择是
and over again because you make an
unlucky choice that is you choose this
一台服务器偶然选择与另一台服务器相同的随机数
one server happens by ill chance to
choose the same random number as another
服务器，这意味着您将永远重复投票
server that means that you're gonna have
split votes over and over again forever
这就是为什么您几乎肯定要选择其他新的随机随机变量的原因
that's why you want to almost certainly
choose a different a new fresh random
每次重置计时器都可以选择选举超时值的编号
number for the election time out value
every time you reset the timer all right
所以关于领导人选举的最后一个问题是假设我们处于这种情况下
so the final issue about leader election
suppose we are in this situation where
旧的领导者分区您知道网络电缆已断开，旧的
the old leaders partition you know the
network cable is broken and the old
领导者那里有几个客户和少数服务器
leader is sort of out there with a
couple clients and a minority of servers
并且网络的另一半占大多数，
and there's a majority in the other half
of the network and the majority of the
网络的新成员选举一位新领导者，那位老领导者又为什么呢？
new half of the network elects a new
leader what about the old leader why why
老领导不会导致执行不正确
won't the old leader cause incorrect
execution
是，针对两个潜在问题，一个是或一个，一些非问题是，如果存在
yes to two potential problems one is or
one some non problem is that if there's
一个领导者离开另一个分区，并且没有下一个分区的多数
a leader off in another partition and it
doesn't have a majority then the next
客户端向它发送请求时，您在分区中认识的那个领导者
time a client sends it a request that
that leader that you know in a partition
是的，它会发送附加条目，但因为它在
with a minority yeah it'll send out
append entries but because it's in the
少数分区，它将无法从大多数
minority partition it won't be able to
get responses back from a majority of
服务器包括它本身，因此它将永远不会提交该操作
the server's including itself and so it
will never commit the operation it will
永远不执行它，永远不会回应客户的说法
never execute it
it'll never respond to the client saying
它执行了它，所以这意味着旧服务器通常
that it executed it either and so that
means that yeah an old server often a
不同的分区，许多客户可能会发送请求，但他们永远都不会得到
different partition people many clients
may send a request but they'll never get
做出回应，因此不会让任何客户误以为该旧服务器
responses so no client will be fooled
into thinking that that old server
为此执行了其他任何更棘手的问题，实际上我会
executed anything for it the other sort
of more tricky issue which actually I'll
在几分钟内谈论的是在服务器故障之前的可能性
talk about in a few minutes is the
possibility that before server fails it
将附加条目发送到一部分服务器，然后在崩溃之前
sends out append entries to a subset of
the servers and then crashes before
提成佣金，作为一个非常有趣的问题，我可能会
making a commission and as a very
interesting question which I'll probably
花了45分钟来讨论，所以实际上在我转向
spend a good 45 minutes talking about
and so actually before I turn to the
返回主题，关于领导者选举的任何其他问题都可以
back topic in general any more questions
about in leader election okay
好吧，那么日志的内容又如何，特别是
okay so how about the contents of the
logs and how in particular how a newly
当选的领导人可能在尴尬的撞车事故后收拾残局
elected leader possibly picking up the
pieces after an awkward crash of the
前任领导人如何重新选举可能产生分歧的新当选领导人
previous leader how does a newly elected
leader sort out the possibly divergent
登录不同的副本，以恢复一致状态
logs on the different replicas in order
to restore sort of consistent state in
系统还可以，所以第一个问题是什么可以认为这是这个
the system all right so the first
question is what can think this is this
整个主题只有在服务器崩溃后才真正有趣，如果
whole topic it's really only interesting
after a server crashes right if the
服务器保持启动状态，那么如果我们有服务器，则相对来说很少会出错
server stays up then relatively few
things can go wrong if we have a server
这是上升的，并且在上升期间您知道的多数
that's up and has a majority you know
during the period of time when it's up
并以多数票数告诉追随者日志的外观
and has a majority it just tells the
followers what the logs should look like
并且不允许追随者不同意他们必须接受他们
and the followers are not allowed to
disagree they're required to accept they
只要按照图二的规则来做，或多或少都会跟上你
知道他们只是接受领导发送给他们的任何独立理由
know they just take whatever the leader
sends them independent reason appended
到日志并服从提交消息并执行，几乎没有什么可做的
to the log and obey commit messages and
execute there's hardly anything to go
当老领导崩溃时，Rapp中出错的地方出错了
wrong the things that go wrong in Rapp
go wrong when a the old leader crashes
在您知道发送消息或新领导导致您崩溃的过程中
sort of midway through you know sending
out messages or a new leader crashes you
在选出之后但做任何事情之前都知道
非常有用，因此我们非常感兴趣的一件事是日志的外观
very useful so one thing we're very
interested in is what can the logs look
像发生了一系列崩溃之后，所以这是一个示例，假设我们有
like after some sequence of crashes okay
so here's an example supposing we have
两台服务器以及我要绘制这些图表的方式，因为我们要
two servers and the way I'm gonna draw
out these diagrams because we're gonna
在很多情况下会看起来像这样的日志
be looking a lot at a lot of sort of
situations where the logs look like this
我们会怀疑这是否可能，如果他们这样做会发生什么
and we're gonna be wondering is that
possible and what happens if they do
看起来像这样，我的记法将是我要写出日志条目
对于每个服务器而言，对齐方式表示插槽对应于
for each of the servers sort of aligned
to indicate slots corresponding slots in
日志和我要在此处写入的值是术语数字，而不是
the log and the values I'm going to
write here are the term numbers rather
比客户操作要多
than
client operations I'm going to you know
这是一个插槽，据认为每个人都看到了第三学期的命令
this is slot one this is thought to
everybody saw a command from term three
在插槽1和服务器调整的服务器3中，也从术语3和
in slot 1 and server tuned server three
saw command from also term three and the
服务器的第二个插槽根本什么都没有，所以对此有疑问
second slot the server one has nothing
there at all and so question for this
像第一个问题是，是否可以到达此设置？
like the very first question is can this
arrive could this setup arise and how
是
yes
所以您知道服务器3只是重复您所说内容的领导者
so you know maybe server 3 was the
leader for just repeating what you said
也许服务器3是第3学期的领导者，他收到了发送给
maybe server 3 is the leader for term 3
he got a command that sent out to
每个人都在日志中收到一个家属，然后我得到了一个服务器3
everybody everybody received a dependent
at the log and then I got a server 3 got
来自客户端的第二个请求，也许它已将其发送到所有三台服务器，但
a second request from a client and maybe
it sent it to all three servers but the
消息在通往服务器一台的途中丢失，或者服务器当时已关闭
message got lost on the way to server
one or maybe server was down at the time
等等，所以只有领导者的服务器总是向其追加新命令
or something and so only server to the
leader always append new commands to its
在发送附加条目之前记录日志，也许附加条目RPC仅得到了
log before it sends out append entries
and maybe the append entry RPC only got
到服务器2，所以这种情况就像最简单的情况一样，
to server 2 so this situation you know
it's like the simplest situation and was
实际上，日志没有什么不同，我们知道它可能如何产生，
actually the logs are not different and
we know how it could possibly arise and
因此，如果现在发生领导崩溃的服务器3，您就知道下一台服务器
so if server 3 which is a leadership
crash now you know the next server
他们将需要首先确保服务器1正常运行，如果服务器3崩溃或
they're gonna need to make sure server 1
well first of all if server 3 crashes or
我们将参加选举，某些领导者被选中，你知道两件事
we'll be at an election and some of the
leader is chosen you know two things
必须发生新领导人必须认识到该命令可能
have to happen the new leader has got to
recognize that this command could have
承诺不允许扔掉它
committed it's not allowed to throw it
away
并且需要确保服务器一号确实在此处填充了此空白
and it needs to make sure server one
fills in this blank here with indeed
其他人在那个插槽中都拥有的同样的命令
this very same command that everybody
else had in that slot all right so after
您认识的服务器3崩溃的人可能会想到的另一种方法是
a crash somebody you know server 3
suppose another way this can come up is
服务器3可能已经向服务器2发送了附加条目，但是随后崩溃了
server 3 might have sent out the append
entries the server 2 but then crashed
在将附加条目发送到服务器3之前，如果您知道选择一个
before sending the append entries to
server 3 so if were you know electing a
新的领导者，这可能是因为在发送消息之前发生了崩溃
new leader it could because we got a
crash before the message was sent
这是再次考虑三台服务器的另一种情况，不，我是说一个数字
here's another scenario to think about
three servers again no I mean a number
法律中的插槽，所以我们可以参考它们，插槽10 11 12 13
the slots in the law and so we can refer
to them got slot 10 11 12 13
[音乐]再次是相同的设置，除了现在我们有
[Music]
again it's same setup except now we have
在幻灯片12中，我们将服务器2作为术语的命令，而服务器3具有一个
in slide 12 we have server 2 as a
command from term for and server 3 has a
第5学期的学期命令
term command from term 5
因此，在我们分析这些信息以了解会发生什么以及发生什么之前
so you know before we analyze these to
figure out what would happen and what
如果服务器看到它，我们会问这是否可能发生，因为
would a server do if it saw this we need
to ask could this even occur because
有时候这个问题的答案哦，哎呀，如果这会发生什么
sometimes the answer to the question oh
jeez what would happen if this
有时会出现配置问题，答案是它不可能出现，所以我们不必
configuration arose sometimes the answer
is it cannot arise so we do not have to
担心它的问题是这会发生吗？
worry about it the question is could
this arise and how
好吧，任何
all right so any
[音乐]
[Music]
是的
yeah
简而言之，我们知道这种配置会出现，因此我们可以
in brief we know this configuration can
arise and so the way we can then get the
我们在下一个领导者选举服务器中假设4和5
four and a five here is let's suppose in
the next leader election server twos
当选领导人现任其当选领导人，因为
elected leader now for term for its
elected leader because a request from a
客户端将其附加到自己的日志中并崩溃，因此现在我们拥有此权限
client it appends it to its own log and
crashes so now we have this right we
需要新的选举，因为领导者在这次选举中刚刚崩溃
need a new election because the leader
just crashed now in this election and
那么现在我们必须问谁可以当选还是我们必须给他
then so now we have to ask whether who
could be elected or we have to give him
哦，天哪，可以当选什么，所以我们要索要服务器
back of our heads oh gosh what could be
elected so we're gonna claim server
三个人可以当选我之所以可以当选是因为
three could be elected the reason why I
could be elected is because it only
需要多数的请求投票答复，多数是服务器一，并且
needs request vote responses from
majority that majority is server one and
服务器三，你知道这两个之间没有冲突没有问题
server three you know there's no no
problem no conflict between these two
记录日志，以便可以为第五任选出第三服务器
logs so server three can be elected for
term five get a request from a client
将其附加到自己的日志中并崩溃，这就是您获得此信息的方式
append it to its own log and crash and
that's how you get this this
配置，因此您知道您需要能够完成这些工作
configuration so you know you need to be
able to to work through these things in
为了到达说是的阶段，这可能会发生，因此漂流
order to get to the stage of saying yes
this could happen and therefore raft
必须做一些明智的事情，而不是做某事，因为某些事情
must do something sensible as opposed to
it cannot happen because some things
不可能发生
can't happen
好吧，所以现在发生了什么，我们知道这会发生，所以希望我们可以
all right so so what can happen now we
know this can occur so hopefully we can
说服自己，筏现在确实做了一些明智的事情，
convince ourselves that raft actually
does something sensible now as for the
在我们讨论英国皇家空军实际上将要做什么之前
range of things before we talk about
what RAF would actually would actually
我们是否需要对可以接受的结果权利有所了解？
do we need to have some sense of what
would be an acceptable outcome right and
我们只知道插槽10中的命令，因为
just eyeballing this we know that the
command in slot 10 since it's known by
它可能已经提交的所有副本，因此我们不能将其丢弃
all all the replicas it could have been
committed so we cannot throw it away
与插槽11中的命令类似，因为它在大多数副本中
similarly the command in slot 11 since
it's in a majority of the replicas it
对于我们所知道的所有已经承诺的事情，我们不能将其扔掉
could for all we know have been
committed so we can't throw it away the
12号插槽中的命令，但是它们都可能未提交
command in slot 12 however neither of
them could possibly have been committed
所以我们有权，我们不知道实际上我们不会，但筏有权
so we're entitled we don't know haven't
we'll actually do but raft is entitled
即使无权删除它们，也可以删除两者
to drop both of these even though it is
not entitled to drop it and either of
10或11中的命令被删除，不是
the commands in a 10 or 11
this is entitled dropped it's not
需要丢掉其中之一，但是我的意思是，它肯定必须丢掉一个
required to drop either one of them but
I mean oh it certainly must drop one at
至少一个，因为最后必须具有相同的日志内容
least one because you have to have
identical log contents in the end
我们可能无法通过查看法律来判断这一点
this could have been committed it the we
can't tell by looking at the laws
确切地说，领导者在坠毁前走了多远，所以一种可能性是
exactly how far the leader got before
crashing so one possibility is that for
这个命令甚至这个命令的一种可能性是领导者发出
this command or even this command one
possibility is that leaders send out the
使用新命令附加消息，然后立即崩溃，因此它从未
append messages with a new command and
then immediately crashed so it never got
因为它崩溃了，所以没有回音，所以这位老领导人不知道那是不是
any response back because it crashed so
the old leader did not know if it was
提交，如果没有回复，则表示没有
committed and if it didn't get a
response back that means it didn't
执行它并没有发出，但您知道它没有发出
execute it and it didn't send out but
you know it didn't send out that
提交索引增加了，所以也许副本也没有执行它，所以
incremented commit index and so maybe
the replicas didn't execute it either so
实际上很有可能没有提交，即使RAF没有
it's actually possible that this wasn't
committed so even though RAF doesn't
如果筏知道的多于它所知道的，那么就知道筏是合法的
know it could be legal for raft
if raft knew more than it does know it
删除此日志条目可能是合法的，因为它可能尚未提交
might be legal to drop this log entry
because it might not have been committed
但是因为没有证据可以证明它是基于事实的
but because on the evidence there's no
way to disprove it was committed based
根据这个证据，它可能已经犯了，筏不能证明它不是
on this evidence it could have been
committed and raft can't prove it wasn't
因此它必须将其视为已落实，因为领导者可能已收到它
so it must treat it as committed because
the leader might have received it might
在收到附加条目回复并回复到
have crashed just after receiving the
append entry replies and replying to the
客户，所以仅查看此内容就不能排除
client so just looking at this we can't
rule out the possibility that either
领导者回应客户的可能性，在这种情况下我们不能丢
possibility that the leader responded to
the client in which case we cannot throw
拒绝此条目，因为客户知道它或领导者的可能性
away this entry because a client knows
about it or the possibility the leader
没做过，是的，我们可以知道是否必须假定它已提交吗？
never did and yeah we could you know if
we have to assume that it was committed
是的
yeah
不，没有mañana服务器崩溃，在得到响应之前还可以
no there's no mañana server crash before
getting the response it's alright well
让我们在星期四继续
let's continue this on Thursday